[
    {
        "question": "What documents must you have with you to fly the airplane? (61.3)",
        "answer": "Pilot certificate, medical certificate, and government issued photo ID. *as a student pilot, these documents in addition to your logbook (to show endorsements) are only required when acting as PIC (solo flight), a) be at least 17 years of age. b) Be able to read, speak, write, and understand the English language. c) Hold at least a current third-class medical certificate. d) Received the required ground and flight training endorsements. e) Meet the applicable aeronautical experience requirements. f) Passed the required knowledge and practical tests. Exam Tip) The evaluator may ask you to demonstrate that your're current and eligible to take the practical test. When preparing for your practical test, verify that you have the required hours, that you're current, and don't forget to double check all of your endorsements (especially the 90-day solo flight endorsement). Make sure you have totaled all of the logbook columns and that the entries make sense."
    },
    {
        "question": "1A1. What are the eligibility requirements for a private pilot (airplane) certificate? (14 CFR 61.103)",
        "answer": "a) be at least 17 years of age. b) Be able to read, speak, write, and understand the English language. c) Hold at least a current third-class medical certificate. d) Received the required ground and flight training endorsements. e) Meet the applicable aeronautical experience requirements. f) Passed the required knowledge and practical tests. Exam Tip) The evaluator may ask you to demonstrate that your're current and eligible to take the practical test. When preparing for your practical test, verify that you have the required hours, that you're current, and don't forget to double check all of your endorsements (especially the 90-day solo flight endorsement). Make sure you have totaled all of the logbook columns and that the entries make sense."
    },
    {
        "question": "1A2. What privileges and limitations apply to a private pilot? (14 CFR 61.113)",
        "answer": "No person who holds a private pilot certificate may act as pilot in command of an aircraft that is carrying passengers or property for compensation or hire; nor may that person, for compensation or hire, act as pilot in command of an aircraft. A private pilot -- a) May act as PIC of an aircraft in connection with any business or employment if it is only incidental to that business or employment and does not carry passengers or property for compensation or hire. b) May not pay less than the pro rata share of the operating expenses of a flight with passengers, provided the expenses involve only fuel, oil, airport expenditures, or rental fees. c) May act as PIC of a charitable, nonprofit, or community event flight described in 14 CFR 91.146, if the sponsor and pilot comply with the requirements of that regulation."
    },
    {
        "question": "1A3. Explain the statement 'may not pay less than pro-rata share of the operating expenses of a flight' (14 CFR 61.113)",
        "answer": "Pro-rata means 'proportional.' The pilot may not pay less than his or her proportional share of the flight's operating expenses with the passengers, provided the expenses involve only fuel, oil, airport expenditures or rental fees."
    },
    {
        "question": "1A4. The annual inspection for your aircraft is now due and you ask several friends that fly with you regularly to contribute money to help you pay for the inspection. Do the regulations allow for these contributions? (14 CFR 61.113)",
        "answer": "No. A private pilot may not pay less than the pro-rata (proportional) share of the operating expenses of a flight with passengers, provided the expenses involve only fuel, oil, airport expenditures or rental fees. Note: The regulation applies to 'the operating expenses of a flight,' and does not allow for the sharing of fixed or long term operating costs of the airplane with passengers."
    },
    {
        "question": "1A5. To act as a required pilot flight crewmember of a civil aircraft, what must a pilot have in his/her physical posession or readily accessible in the aircraft? (14 CFR 61.3)",
        "answer": "a) A pilot certificate (or special purpose pilot authorization. b) A photo identification. c) A medical certificate (with certain exceptions as provided in 14 CFR 61.3)"
    },
    {
        "question": "1A6. While you are performing a preflight inspection on your aircraft, an inspector from the FAA introduces herself and says she wants to conduct a ramp inspection. What documents are you required to show the inspector? (14 CFR 16.3)",
        "answer": "Each person who holds an airman certificate, medical certificate, authorization, or license required by Part 61 must present it and their photo identification for inspection upon a request from the administrator, an authorized NTSB representative, any federal, state, or local law enforcement officeer, or an authorized representative of the TSA."
    },
    {
        "question": "1A7. What is the definition of a high-performance airplane, and what must you do to act as pilot-in-command of such an airplane? (14 CFR 61.31)",
        "answer": "A high-performance is an airplane with an engine of more than 200 horsepower. To act as PIC of a high-performance you must have: a). Received and logged ground and flight training from an authorized instructor in a high-performance airplane, or in a flight simulator or flight training device that is representative of a high-performance airplane, and have been found proficient in the operation and systems of the at airplane. b) Received and logged a one-time endorsement in your logbook from an authorized instructor who certifies you are proficient to operate a high-performance airplane. Note: The training and endorsement required by this regulation is not required if hte person has logged flight time as PIC of a high-performance airplane, or in a flight simulator or flight training device that is representative of a high-performance airplane prior to August 4, 1997."
    },
    {
        "question": "1A8. Other than high-performance and complex aircraft, what other types of aircraft (ASEL) require specific training and logbook endorsements from an appropriately rated flight instructor? (14 CFR 61.31)",
        "answer": "High-altitude airplane0 No person may act as PIC of a pressurized airplane that has a service ceiling or maximum operating altitude (whichever is lower), above 25,000 feet MSL unless that person has completed the ground and flight training specified and has received a logbook or training record endorsement from an authorized instructor certifying satisfactory completion of the training. Tailwheel airplane - No person may act as PIC of a tailwheel airplane unless that person has received and logged flight training from an authorized instructor in a tailwheel airplane and received an endorsement in the person's logbook from an authorized instructor who found the person proficient in the operation of a tailwheel airplane. The training and endorsement is not required if the person logged PIC time in a tailwheel plane before April 15, 1991."
    },
    {
        "question": "1A9. What is the definition of a complex airplane, and what must you do to act as PIC of such an airplane? (14 CFR 61.1, 61.31)",
        "answer": "A 'complex airplane' is defined as an airplane that has a retractable landing gear, flaps, and a controllable pitch propellar, including airplanes equipped with a full-authority digital engine control (FADEC). To act as PIC of such an airplane, you must have: a). Received and logged ground and flight training from an authorized instructor in a complex airplane, or in a flight simulator or flight training device that is representative of a complex airplane and have been found proficient in the operation and systems of the airplane. b) Received a one-time endorsement in your logbook from an authorized instructor who certifies you are proficient to operate a complex airplane. Note: The training and endorsement required by this regulation is not required if the person has logged flight time as PIC of a complex airplane, or in a flight simulator or flight training device that is representative of a complex airplane prior to August 4, 1997."
    },
    {
        "question": "1A10. With respect to certification, privileges, and limitations of airmen, define the terms: category, class, and type. (14 CFR Part 1)",
        "answer": "Category- a broad classification of aircraft; i.e., airplane, rotorcraft, glider, etc. Class- a classification of aircraft within a category having similar operating characteristics; i.e., single-engine land, multi-engine land; etc. Type- a specific make and basic model of aircraft including momdifications that do not change its handling or flight characteristics; i.e., DC-9, B-737, C-150, etc."
    },
    {
        "question": "1B1. What are the requirements to remain current as a private pilot? (14 CFR 61.56, 61.57)",
        "answer": "a) Within the preceding 24 months, accomplished a flight review given in an aircraft for which that pilot is rated by an authorized instructor and received a logbook endorsement certifying that the person has satisfactorily completed the review. b) To carry passengers, a pilot must have made, within the preceding 90 days: 1: three takeoffs and landings as the sole mainipulator of flight controls of an aircraft of the same category and class and, if a type rating is required, of the same type. 2: if the aircraft is a tailwheel airplane, the landings must have been made to a full stop in an airplane with a tailwheel. 3: if operations are to be conducted during the period beginning 1 hour after sunset and 1 hour before sunrise, with passengers on board, the PIC must have, within the preceding 90 days, made at least three takeoffs and three landings to a full stop during that period in an aircraft of the same category, class, and type (if a type is required), of aircraft ot be used. Note: Takeoffs and landings requried by this regulation may be accomplished in a flight simulator or flight training device that is approved by the Administrator and used in accordance with an approved course conducted by a certificated training center."
    },
    {
        "question":"1B2. You have not kept up with your logging each of your recent flights. Are you in violation of any regulation? (14 CFR 61.51)",
        "answer":"No. You're only required to document and record the training and aeronautical experience used to meet the requirements for a certificate, rating, or flight review, and the aeronautical experience required for meeting the recent flight experience requirements."
    },
    {
        "question":"1B3. You're flying in a single-engine, high performancec, complex airplane. You hold a Private Pilot certification with an airplane single-engine land rating, but don't have a high-performance or complex airplane endorsement. Your friend, who has those endorsements, is acting as PIC for the flight. Can you log PIC time for the time you act as sole manipulator of the controls? Explain (14 CFR 61.31, 61.51)",
        "answer":"Yes. 14 CFR 61.51 governs the logging of PIC time and states that a sport, recreational, private, commercial, or airline transport pilot may log PIC time for the time during which that pilot is 'sole manipulator of the controls of an aircraft for which the pilot is rated or has privileges.'  Note: This means you can log PIC time, but you cannot act as PIC. For a pilot to act as PIC, he or she must be properly rated in the aircraft and authorized to conduct the flight which would include having th erequired endorsements for complex and high performance airplanes as required by 14 CFR 61.31. "
    },
    {
        "question":"1B4. Explain the difference between bebing 'current' and being 'proficient'. (FAA-H-808302, FAA-P-8740-36)",
        "answer":"Being 'current' means that a pilot has accomplished the minimum FAA regulatory requirements within a specific time period so he or she can exercise th eprivileges of their certificate. It means that you're 'legal' to make a flight, but does not necessarily mean that you're proficient or competent to make that flight.  Being 'proficient' means that a pilot is capable of conducting a flight with a high degree of competence; it requires that the pilot must have a wide range of knowledge and skills. Being proficient is not about just being 'legal' in terms mof the regulations, but is about being 'smart' and 'safe' in terms of pilot experience and proficiency."
    },
    {
        "question":"1B5. How will establishing a personal minimums checklist reduce risk? (FAA-H8083-25)",
        "answer":"Professional pilots live by the numbers, and so should you. Pre-established numbers can make it a lot easier to come to a smart go/no-go or diversion decision, than would the vague sense that you can 'probably' deal with the conditions you face at any given time. A written set of personal minimums also make it easier to explain tough cancelation or diversion decisions to passengers who are, after all, trusting their lives to your aeronautical skill and judgement."
    },
    {
        "question":"1B6. The airplane you normally rent has been grounded due to an intermittent electrical problem. You ask to be scheduled in another airplane. During preflight of the new airplane, you dicscover that it has avionics you're unfamiliar with. Should you go ahead and depart on your VFR flight? (FAA-H8083-2)",
        "answer":"Pilot familiarity with all equipment is critical in optimizing both safety and efficiency. If a pilot is unfamiliar with any aircraft systems, this will add to workload and can contribute to a loss of situational awareness. This level of profiicency is critical and should be looked upon as a requirement, not unlike carrying an adequate supply of fuel. As a result, pilots should not look upon unfamiliarity with the aircraft and its systems as a risk control measure, but instead as a hazard with high risk potential.  Discipline is the key to success."
    },
    {
        "question":"1B7. If a pilot changes his/her permanent mailing address and fials to notify the FAA Airmen Certification branch of the new address, how long may the pilot continue to exercise the privileges of his/her pilot certificate? (14 CFR 61.60)",
        "answer":"30 days after the date of the move."
    },
    {
        "question":"1B8. What flight time can a pilot log as second-in-command time? (14 CFR 60.51)",
        "answer":"A person may log second-in-command (SIC) time only for the flight time during which that person: a) Is qualified in accordance with the SIC requirements of 14 CFR 60.55, and occupies a crewmember station in an aircraft that requires more than one pilot by the aircraft's type certificate, or b) Holds the appropriate category, class, and instrument rating (if an instrument rating is required for the flight) for the aircraft being flown, and more than one pilot is required under the type certification of the aircraft or the regulations under which the flight is being conducted."
    },
    {
        "question":"1C1. To exercise the privileges of a private pilot certificate what medical certificate is required, and how long is it valid? (14 CFR 61.23 and Part 68)",
        "answer":"You must hold at least a third-class medical certificate. The medical certificate expires at the end of the last day of: A). The 60th month after the month of the date of examination shown on the certificate, if on the date of your most recent medical examination you were under the age of 40. B) The 24th month after the month of the date of examination shown on the certificate, if on the date of your most recent medical examination you were over the age of 40. Note: Third class medical reform went into effect in 2017, eliminating the need for a 3rd class medical certificate for many. Check FAA.gov for updates on this Part 68 'BasicMed'"
    },
    {
        "question":"1c2. Spring has finally arrived and the weather looks great so you decide to rent an airplane and go fly. The problem is, your allergies are giving you a problem and you have just taken your medication. Can you still go fly? Explane. (14 CFR 61.53, 91.17, FAA-H-8083-25)",
        "answer":"The safest rule is to not fly while taking any medication, unless approved to do so by the FAA. Some of the most commonly used over-the-counter (OTC) drugs, antihistamines and decongestants, have the potential to cause noticeable adverse side effects, including drowsiness and cognitive deficits. 14 CFR prohibits pilots from performing crew member duties while using any medication that affects the body in any way contrary to safety. If there is any doubt regarding the effects of any medication, consult an Aviation Medical Examiner (AME) before flying. Note: Info on the FAA's 'Do not issue/do not fly' medications can be found at: FAA.gov/about/office_org/headquarters_offices/avs/offices/aam/ame/guide/pharm/"
    },
    {
        "question":"1c3. Where can you go find a list of the medical conditions that may disqualify you from obtaining a medical certificate? (14 CFR Part 67, FAA-H-8083-25)",
        "answer":"The standards for medical certification are contained in Part 67 and the requirements for obtaining medical certificates can be found in Part 61."
    },
    {
        "question":"1c4. What requirements must be met to fly under BasicMed? (AC 68-1)",
        "answer":"A) hold a current and valid U.S. driver's license    B) Hold or have held a medical certificate issued by the FAA at any point after July 14, 2006   C) answer the health questions on the Comprehensive Medical Examination Checklist (CMEC)   D) get your physical examination by any State—licensed physician, and have that physician complete the CMEC (be sure to keep your copy of the CMEC)   E) Take a BasicMed online medical education course. Keep the course completion document issued to you by the course provider."
    },
    {
        "question":"1c4. What requirements must be met to fly under BasicMed? (AC 68-1)",
        "answer":"A) hold a current and valid U.S. driver's license     B) Hold or have held a medical certificate issued by the FAA at any point after July 14, 2006    C) answer the health questions on the Comprehensive Medical Examination Checklist (CMEC)    D) get your physical examination by any State—licensed physician, and have that physician complete the CMEC (be sure to keep your copy of the CMEC)   E) Take a BasicMed online medical education course. Keep the course completion document issued to you by the course provider."
    },
    {
        "question":"1c5. What privileges and limitations apply when flying under BasicMed? (14 CFR 61.113, AC 68-1)",
        "answer":"You can conduct any operation that you would otherwise be able to conduct using your pilot certificate and a third-class medical certificate, except you are limited too:   A). Fly with no more than five passengers.    B) fly an aircraft that has a maximum takeoff weight of not more than 6,000 pounds    C) fly an aircraft that is authorized to carry no more than six occupants (i.e. five passengers plus the pilot)    D) flights within the US, at an indicated airspeed of 250 knots or less, and at an altitude at or below 18,000 feet MSl.    E) you may not fly for compensation or hire"
    },
    {
        "question":"1c6. What is required to maintain BasicMed privileges? (AC 68-1)",
        "answer":"A) be sure you have a CMEC that shows that your most recent physical examination was within the past 48 months. Keep the completed, signed CMEC in a safe place.    B) be sure you are being treated by a physician for medical conditions that may affect safety of flight.    C) be sure you have a course completion certificate that was issued by a BasicMed medical training course provider within the past 24 calendar months."
    },
    {
        "question":"1.1. One way a pilot can limit exposure to risks is to set personal minimums for items in each risk category (PAVE). Describe the individual minimums you will establish for yourself. (FAA-H-8083-2)",
        "answer":"[Insert here]"
    },
    {
        "question":"1.2. As a newly certificate private pilot, you are ready to utilize your certificate. I'm a friend and need you to fly a package to a distant destination. I will pay you for the airplane if you accept. Do the regulations allow you to accept the offer? (14 CFR 61.113)",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"1.3. For a person under the age of 40, when will a third class medical certificate issued on March 15, 2020 expire? ((14 CFR 61.60)",
        "answer":"60 months (5 years) after issued -> March 31, 2025"
    },
    {
        "question":"1.4. What are some examples of general medical conditions that are temporarily disqualifying? (AIM 8-1-1, 14 CFR 61.53)",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"1.5. If your driver's license was recently suspended for driving under the influence of alcohol (DUI), but you have not been actually convicted of the crime, must you report this to the FAA? (14 CFR 61.15)",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"1.6. You have allowed over 24 months to lapse since your last flight review. Is your Private Pilot Certificate now invalid? What do you have to do to be legal to fly again? (14 CFR 61.19, 14 CFR 61.56)",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"1.7. Are there any other activities a pilot can accomplish that can be substituted for a flight review? (14 CFR 61.56)",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"1.8. What regulatory requirements must be met prior to a pilot acting as PIC of an aircraft towing a glider? (14 CFR 61.69)",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"2a1. What documents are required on board an aircraft prior to flight? (14 CFR 91.203, 91.9)",
        "answer":"ARROW     A)irworthiness certificate (14 CFR 91.203)     R)egistration certificate (14 CFR 91.203)      R)adió station license (if operating outside of US; an FCC regulation)      O)pirating Limitations- AFM/POH and supplements, placards, markings (14 CFR 9.1.9)       W)eight and balance data (current)     Compass Deviation Card (14 CFR 23.1547)       External Data Plate/Serial Number (14 CFR 45.11)      Exam tip: during the practical test your evaluator may wish to examine the various required aircraft documents (arrow) during the preflight inspection, as well as the currency of any aeronautical charts, EFB data, etc. On board the aircraft. Prior to the test, verify that all the necessary aircraft documentation, on-board databases and charts are current and available."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a2. What is an airworthiness certificate? (FAA-H-8083-25)",
        "answer":"An airworthiness certificate is issued by the FAA to an aircraft that has been proven to meet the minimum design and manufacturing requirements and is condition for safe operation. Under any circumstances, the aircraft must meet the requirements of the original type certificate or it is no longer airworthy. These certificates come in two different classifications: standard airworthiness and special airworthiness."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a3. What is the difference between standard and special airworthiness certificates? (FAA-H-8083-25)",
        "answer":"Standard airworthiness certificates (white paper) are issued for normal, utility, acrobatic, commuter, or transport category aircraft. Special airworthiness certificates (pink paper) are issued for primary, restricted, or limited category aircraft, and light sport aircraft."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a4. What is an experimental airworthiness certificate? (FAA-H-8083-25)",
        "answer":"A special airworthiness certificate in the experimental category is issued to operate an aircraft that does not have a type certificate or does not conform to its type certificate yet is in a condition for safe operation. Additionally, this certificate is issued to operate a primary category kit-built aircraft tha twas assembled without the supervision and quality control of the production certificate holder."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a5. Does an airworthiness ceretificate have an expiration date? (FAA-H-8083-25)",
        "answer":"No. A standard airworthiness certificate remains valid for as long as the aircraft meets its approved type design, is in a condition for safe operation, and the maintenacne preventative maintenance, and alterations are performed in accordance with Parts 21, 43, and 91."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a6. Where must the airworthiness certificate be located? (14 CFR 91.203, FAA-H-8083-19)",
        "answer":"The certificate must be displayed at the cabin or cockpit entrance so that it is legible to passengers or crew."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a7. For an aircraft to be considered airworthy, what two conditions must be met? (FAA-H-8083-19)",
        "answer":"A) The aircraft mus tconform to its type design (type certificate). This is attained when the required and proper components are installed consistent with the drawings, specifications, and other data that are part of the type certificate. Conformity includes applicable supplemental type certificate(s) (STC) and field-approval alterations.   B) The aircraft mus tbe in a condition for safe operation, referring to the condition of the aircraft in relation to wear and deterioration."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a8. Explain how a pilot determines if an aircraft conforms to its approved type design and is in a condition for safe operation. (14 CFR Part 21)",
        "answer":"A) For type design, a pilot must determine that the maintenance, preventive maintenance, and alterations have been performed in accordance Parts 21, 43, and 91 and that the aircraft is registered in the U.S. The pilot does this by ensuring that all required inspections, maintenance, preventive maintenance, repairs and alterations have been appropriately documented in the aircraft's maintenance records.   B) For safe operation, the pilot conducts a thorough preflight inspection of the aircraft for wear adn deterioration, structural damage, fluid leaks, tire wear, inoperative instruments and equipment, etc. If an unsafe condition exists or inoperative instruments or equipment are found, the pilot uses the guidance in 14 CFR 91.213 for handling the inoperative equipment."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a9. What records or documents should beb checked to determine that the owner or operator of an aircraft has complied with all required inspections and airworthiness directives? (14 CFR 91.405)",
        "answer":"The maintenance records (aircraft and engine logbooks). Each owner or operator of an aircraft shall ensure that maintenance personnel make appropriate entries in the aircraft maintenance records indicating the aircraft has been approved for return to service."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a10. Who is responsible for ensuring that an aircraft is maintained in an airworthy condition? (14 CFR 91.403)",
        "answer":"The owner or operator of an aircraft is primarily responsible for maintaining an aircraft in an airworthy condition."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a11. Describe some of the responsibilities an aircraft owner has pertaining to aircraft documents, maintenance, and inspections of their aircraft. (FAA-H-8083-25)",
        "answer":"Aircraft owners must:   A) Have a current airworthiness certificate and aircraft registration in the aircraft.  B) Maintain the aircraft in an airworthy condition including compliance with all applicable Airworthiness Directives.   C) Ensure maintenance is properly recorded.   D)Keep abreast of current regulations concerning the operation of that aircraft.   E) Notify the FAA Civil Aviation Registry immediately of any change of permanent mailing address, or of the sale or export of the aircraft, or of the loss of citizenship.  F) Have a current FCC radio station license if equipped with radios, including emergency locator transmitter (ELT), if operated outside of the United States."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a12. What are airworthiness Directives (AD)? (FAA-H-8083-25)",
        "answer":"An AD is the medium by which the FAA notifies aircraft owners and other potentially interested persons of unsafe conditions that may exist because of design defects, maintenance, or other causes, and specifies the conditions under which the product may continue to be operated. ADs are regulatory in nature, and compliance is mandatory. It is the aircraft owner's or operator's responsibility to ensure compliance with all pertinent ADs."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a13. What are the two types of ADs? (FAA-H-8083-19)",
        "answer":"ADs are divided into two categories: Those of an emergency nature requiring immediate compliance prior to further flight, and those of a less urgent nature requiring compliance within a specified period of time."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a14. When are emergency ADs issued? (FAA-H-8083-19)",
        "answer":"An emergency AD is issued when an unsafe condition exists that requires immediate action by an owner/operator. The intent of an emergency AD is to rapidly correct an urgent safety-of-flilght situation. All known owners and operators of affected U.S.-registered aircraft or those aircraft that have an affected product installed will be sent a copy of an emergency AD.   Exam Tip: ADs and recurring ADs - be capable of finding and explaining the status of all ADs and recurring ADs that exist for your aircraft. Locate and tab prior to the practical test. "
    },
    {
        "question":"2a15. While reviewing the aircraft logbooks, you discover that your aircraft is not in compliance with an AD's specific time or date. Are you allowed to continue to operate that aircraft until the next required maintenance inspection? Do the regulations allow any kind of buffer? (AC 39-7)",
        "answer":"The assumpiton that AD compliance is only required at the time of a required inspection (e.g., at a 100-hour or annual inspection) is not correct. The required compliance time/date is specified in each AD and no person may operate the affected product after expiration of that stated compliance time without an Alternative Method of Compliance (AMOC) approval for a change in compliance time."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a16. You determine that you need to fly your aircraft with an expired AD to another airport where the repair facility can do the work required by the AD. How can you accomplish this? (AC 39-7, 14 CFR 21.199)",
        "answer":"Unless the AD states otherwise, you may apply to the FAA for a special flight permit following the procedures in 14 CFR 21.199"
    },
    {
        "question":"2a17. What is a type certificate data sheet? (FAA-H-8083-30)",
        "answer":"The FAA issues a type certificate when a new aircraft, engine, propeller, etc. is found to meet safety standards set forth by the FAA. The type certificate data sheet (TCDS) lists the specifications, conditions and limitations under which airworthiness requirements were met for the specified product, such as engine make and model, fuel type, engine limits, airspeed limits, maximum weight, minimum crew, etc. "
    },
    {
        "question":"2a18. What is a supplemental type certificate? (FAA-H-8083-3, FAA-H-8083-30, AC 21-40)",
        "answer":"A supplemental type certificate (STC) is the FAA's approval of a major change in the type design of a previously approved type certificated product. The certificate authorizes an alteration to an airframe, engine, or component that has been granted an approved type certificate. Sometimes alterations are made that are not specified or authorized in the TCDS. When that condition exists, an STC will be issued. STCs are considered a part of the permanent records of an aircraft, and should be maintained as part of that aircraft's logs."
    },
    {
        "question":"2a19. What is an aircraft registration certificate? (FAA-H-8083-25)",
        "answer":"Before an aircraft can be flown legally, it must be registered with the FAA Aircraft Registry. The Certificate of Aircraft Registration, which is issued to the owner as evidence of the registration, must be carried in the aircraft at all times."
    },
    {
        "question":"",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"",
        "answer":""
    }
]